Career preparation, module six.
This one I feel is an extremely important,
I know I've been saying that for the different modules,
but an extremely important module.
I didn't really do any of this until my graduate program
or the senior year of my undergraduate.
But yeah, identify the corgum onto the resume.
You know, go to the career center.
This is the career center module.
Go to the career center, you know,
talk to somebody about making your resume.
And your resume doesn't have to have extensive experience.
If you hadn't had a job before, that's fine.
Just add whatever you need to do, you know,
use action verbs.
Build a LinkedIn profile.
You feel free to look at my LinkedIn profile.
You might find it, just search up my name on LinkedIn.
Feel free to look at my program advisor,
Dr. Turner, Dr. Todd Turner.
His LinkedIn is a great example of what a LinkedIn
should look like a professional LinkedIn.
Describe two concrete network strategies.
Networking is crucial.
I have gotten really far in, you know,
career preparation with networking, talking to alumni.
Locate your career center, very important.
The career center will help you out.
You know, there will be Zoom options if you want virtual,
in-person options if you want.
UNC's career center uses handshake,
but also you can go into the career center,
you know, hide your resume, tell them,
I want to go to the resume, or I'm applying for this job,
but I don't know how to bypass the applicant tracking system,
the ATS.
They will help you tailor your resume
to apply for those jobs.
The career center is a great way to, you know,
push yourself forward to making sure
that you are career ready.
Outside of my undergraduate degree,
I was not career ready.
I didn't know what to do.
And now that I'm in my master's program,
I have a LinkedIn, I have a resume,
I've been applying to multiple different jobs.
I am career ready, I've been doing interviews.
Career center will help me with interviews as well.
So, you know, if you, you know,
you may think that this isn't important necessarily right now,
but getting a solid resume and a LinkedIn
doesn't even have to be a lot of information,
but getting those at least out there
will take you a long way.
So I hope you take a lot out of
the bottom six career preparation.